<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinko Dermendzhiev</title>
    <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dinko Dermendzhiev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a Convolutional Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>To understand the basics of image-based machine learning and create a process that you can later analyze in memory, you must first build a machine learning model. You will be using PyTorch to create a model for the CIFAR10 dataset.
Create a Python file and import the necessary libraries. import torch import torchvision import torchvision.transforms as transforms Download the CIFAR10 train and test datasets and normalize the images. transform = transforms.Compose( [transforms.ToTensor(), transforms.Normalize((0.5, 0.5, 0.5), (0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspect the Running Python ML Process</title>
      <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Set a breakpoint at the forward pass of test data. images, labels = data breakpoint() outputs = net(images) # forward pass of test data Start the neural network python file using GDB. $ gdb python3 (gdb) run [PATH_TO_FILE]/[FILENAME].py When the process reaches the breakpoint you previously set, control will be transferred to PDB. Print out the hex memory locations of a few objects in the Python process. Print out the fields/attributes of the objects. Return to GDB by pressing Ctrl + C.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gather a Memory Image of the System</title>
      <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>With the process still running, you will now take a snapshot of RAM for memory forensics purposes.
Clone the LiME repo on the machine running the ML Process. $ git clone https://github.com/504ensicsLabs/LiME Enter the src directory and compile LiME. Note: Since you are already on the target machine, LiME will detect the system&amp;rsquo;s OS kernel and build accordingly. In a real world scenario, you might not have access to the target machine, and even if you do, compilation will perturb the state of volatile memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspect the Memory Image</title>
      <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Make sure you have Volatility cloned and setup. Note: You will be using the current standard, Volatility3. Once cloned locally, you will see the volatility3 directory, which contains everything you need. Run the following commands to setup Volatility3 with full functionality.
/volatility3$ pip3 install -r requirements.txt Now, you must make sure Volatility3 has access to an ISF file (interactive symbol format) of the target system kernel. Simply put, this is a mapping of how and where the kernel stores it&amp;rsquo;s information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Develop a Volatility Plugin to Recover ML Models</title>
      <link>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ddermendzhiev.github.io/docs/memoryforensicsonml/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The goal is to create a Volatility3 plugin that will traverse through the memory image to find PyTorch models and extract their attributes and data. The runtime state of a Python process is managed by a structure called PyRuntimeState. How can you locate this object in your memory image?
Find the Python3 exe in your file system. Now use readelf with the -s flag to output the symbol table of the file. Pipe the output through grep, searching for &amp;lsquo;PyRuntime&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
